Guide to the Engin Ozendes Collection of Ottoman photography AD.MC.012
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
- Ras Beirut seen from a cliff on the side of a harbor. 20.5 x 26.9 cm, Circa 1870; 4293; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Water; Lebanon; Buildings; Fishing; Boats/Ships; Beirut, Lebanon
- Beiteddine Palace, Lebanon. 20.5 x 27 cm, Circa 1880; 4294; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Fountains; Gelatin Silver Prints; Lebanon; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Men; Architecture; Palaces
- Temple of the Sun (also called the Temple of Jupiter) in Baalbek, Lebanon. 20.5 x 27 cm, Circa 1880; 4295; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Temples; Baalbek, Lebanon; Religious Sites
- Port of Mersin, Turkey (Port de Mersina, Syria). 20.5 x 27 cm, Circa 1870; 4296; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Boats/Ships; Mersin, Turkey; Ports; Photographic Prints; Boats/Ships; Gelatin Silver Prints; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Buildings; Water
- Building interior with furnishings. In the foreground stands a couch, round table and four upholstered spindle-back chairs. 35 x 27.8 cm, Undated; 4297; Bonfils, Felix (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Architecture; Furnishings
- Columns of the Temple of the Sun (also called the Temple of Jupiter) and surrounding ruins in Baalbek, Lebanon. 27.8 x 35.1 cm, Undated; 4298; Bonfils, Felix (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Temples; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Photographic Prints; Baalbek, Lebanon; Albumen Prints; Religious Sites; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- Man with a mustache standing with his right arm on a column in a long, dark jacket, light vest and shirt, a dark bow tie and a ring on his right little finger. 10.5 x 6.2 cm, Undated; 4299; Bonfils, Felix (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Jewelry; Bow Ties; Carpets/Rugs; Facial Hair; Men; Syria; Beirut, Lebanon; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints
- Woman wearing a light colored lace-trimmed top. 41.4 x 34.3 cm, 25 [...?] 1916; 4300; Samanci, Asil; Studio Photo Apollon, Asil Samanci (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women; Greek Writing
- Woman with a crescent shaped hair ornament. 43 x 35 cm, 1910; 4301; Samanci, Asil; Studio Photo Apollon, Asil Samanci (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Women; Jewelry; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Albumen Prints
- Tomb of Sultan Murad II in the Muradiye Complex, Bursa, Turkey. The tomb sits on a stone pedestal and exposed soil can be seen on the surface of the tomb. 31.6 x 35.5 cm, Undated; 4312; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Bursa, Turkey; Religious Sites; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Tombs; Muradiye Complex
- Gate of the Sultan at Dolmabahce Palace, Istanbul, Turkey. 31.8 x 36.8 cm, Undated; 4321; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Architecture; Dolmabahce Palace; Palaces; Buildings
- The Great Mabeyn Pavilion at Yildiz Palace, Istanbul, Turkey. 31.7 x 34.4 cm, Undated; 4328; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Architecture; Yildiz Palace; Palaces; Buildings
- Fountain on a street with the Aziziye Mosque in the background. 31.8 x 36.4 cm, Undated; 4335; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Albumen Prints; Mosques; Outdoors; Street Vendors; Fountains; Men; Horses; Architecture; Konya, Turkey; Aziziye Mosque; Animals; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
- Sultan Ahmed Mosque (The Blue Mosque) Istanbul, Turkey. 32 x 42.6 cm, Undated; 4339; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Religious Sites; Outdoors; Blue Mosque/Sultan Ahmed Mosque; Mosques; Architecture; Istanbul, Turkey; Buildings
- Ablution fountain in the courtyard of Selimiye Mosque in Edirne, Turkey. A group of men gather around the fountain, looking toward the camera. French writing on front. 29.9 x 43 cm, 1894; 4341; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  French Writing; Religious Sites; Men; Architecture; Fountains; Mosques; Selimiye Mosque; Photographic Prints; Edirne, Turkey; Albumen Prints
- Dolmabahce Mosque with ships sailing in the Bosphorus in the background. 32.1 x 43.3 cm, Undated; 4342; Studio Photographie Parisienne, Izmir, Turkey (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Boats/Ships; Architecture; Istanbul, Turkey; Bosphorus; Dolmabahce Mosque; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings
- Family portrait. 32.8 x 40 cm, 1930; 4343; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Furnishings; Girls; Women; Men; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Group Portraits; Children
- Ramla, the Tower of the 40 Martyrs (White Mosque). 20.3 x 25.7 cm, 1865; 4344; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout (Lebanon) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Ramla/ar-Ramlah; White Mosque, Ramla; Architecture; Men; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Churches; Religious Sites; Palestine; Mosques
- Panorama of the city of Ramla with a graveyard in the foreground. 20.6 x 26.9 cm, Circa 1870; 4345; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout (Lebanon) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Outdoors; Buildings; Landscapes; Cemeteries; Tombs; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Ramla/ar-Ramlah; Religious Sites
- Pine forest, Beirut. 20.3 x 26.9 cm, Undated; 4346; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout (Lebanon) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Men; Children; Camels; Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Beirut, Lebanon; Animals; Outdoors; Parks
- "Portrait of two Mahometan Women," one standing, one sitting with a drum, dressed as an odalisque and servant. 26.9 x 20.4 cm, Circa 1893; 4347; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout (Lebanon); Comtesse de Croix-Mesnil (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Beirut, Lebanon; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Regional/National Dress; Jewelry; Albumen Prints; Musical Instruments; Painted Backdrops; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Women; Group Portraits
- Woman wearing a light veil. 35.1 x 27.8 cm, Undated; 4348; Comtesse de Croix-Mesnil; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout (Lebanon) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Women; Individual Portraits; Jewelry; Head Covers/Veils; Turkey; Studio Photography
- Two women in national dress, one standing holding a tambourine, one holding the hose of a shisha pipe. 35 x 27.8 cm, Circa 1870; 4349; Comtesse de Croix-Mesnil; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout (Lebanon) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Musical Instruments; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Regional/National Dress; Women; Smoking; Painted Backdrops; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Head Covers/Veils; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Group Portraits
- Two tents in the Forest of the Cedars of God in the Kadisha Valley in Lebanon. 27.8 x 35 cm, Circa 1870; 4350; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout (Lebanon) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Forest of the Cedars of God, Ariz, Lebanon; Kadisha Valley, Lebanon; Lebanon; Outdoors
- Still-life of a cedar branch and cones with some stones at the bottom. Taken on Mount Lebanon. 35 x 27.8 cm, Undated; 4351; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout (Lebanon) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Lebanon; Forest of the Cedars of God, Ariz, Lebanon; Outdoors; Mount Lebanon/Jabal lubnān, Lebanon; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints
- Tekkiye Mosque (Sultan Selim Mosque) on the banks of the Barada River in Damascus. 27.8 x 35 cm, Undated; 4352; Studio Dumas Photagraphe a Beyrout (Lebanon) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Albumen Prints; Damascus, Syria; Barada River; Rivers; Religious Sites; Tekkiye Mosque; Mosques; Architecture; Photographic Prints
- First Lieutenant Mahmud Nedim with dozens of soldiers standing on a battlefield in military uniforms and fezes. 26.8 x 33 cm, 24 August 1907; 4379; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Men; Military/Soldiers; Ottoman Writing; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Wars; Weapons; Swords/Knives; Fezes/Tarbouches; Outdoors; Guns; Cannons; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- First Lieutenant Mahmud Nedim. 26.8 x 33 cm, 24 August 1907; 4380; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Military/Soldiers; Turkish Writing; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Men; Wars; Guns; Cannons; Fezes/Tarbouches; Outdoors; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Swords/Knives; Military/Soldiers; Weapons; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- Group photo of soldiers with mustaches, some with beards, wearing military uniforms and fezes. 27 x 32.3 cm, Undated; 4381; Z.G. Donatosian (Baghdad, Iraq) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Carpets/Rugs; Facial Hair; Weapons; Fezes/Tarbouches; Swords/Knives; Baghdad, Iraq; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Military/Soldiers; Group Portraits
- Group photo of uniformed soldiers with mustaches wearing fezes, many of whom are holding swords. In the background, a line of men stand on a terrace overhead. 26.7 x 32.5 cm, Undated; 4382; Studio Photographie Parisienne, Izmir, Turkey (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Baghdad, Iraq; Men; Weapons; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Facial Hair; Military/Soldiers; Swords/Knives; Military/Soldiers; Fezes/Tarbouches; Group Portraits
- Entrance to Yedikule Fortress, with a man in dark clothing and a fez standing in the foreground on an approaching dirt road. 27.1 x 33.1 cm, Undated; 4383; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Outdoors; Men; Forts/Castles; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Architecture
- Selimiye Mosque on the left and the Old Mosque of Edirne on the right. In the middle ground, carts with barrels and people are pulled by oxen and in the foreground, a boy sits smiling, looking at the camera. 23.6 x 30.2 cm, 1890; 4384; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Children; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Boys; Men; Animals; French Writing; Old Mosque, Edirne; Mosques; Edirne, Turkey; Selimiye Mosque; Architecture; Cattle/Cows; Carriages/Coaches; Buildings; Architecture; Religious Sites
- Arab woman wearing a veil, looking to her left, wearing an intricate metal necklace and holding her left hand to her chest. On reverse side of ref274. 29.9 x 23.6 cm., Undated; 4385; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Jewelry; Individual Portraits; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Head Covers/Veils; Studio Photography; Albumen Prints; Women
- Two veiled women, carrying water pots on their heads, and a child seated on the ground in between them. On reverse side of ref273. 29.9 x 23.6 cm., Undated; 4386; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Furnishings; Women; Pottery; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Egypt; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Children; Architecture
- Portrait of a couple. Woman wearing a veil and man wearing a military cap and mustache. 29.3 x 19.6 cm., Undated; 4387; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Facial Hair; Uniforms; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Regional/National Dress; Military/Soldiers; Head Covers/Veils; Women; Men; Facial Hair; Group Portraits
- First Lieutenant Ismail Hakki angled to his left, wearing a suit, tie, striped white shirt and mustache. 25.9 x 20.3 cm., Undated; 4388; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Turkish Writing; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Men; Ottoman Writing; Turkey; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography
- Man with small toothbrush mustache, wearing a three-piece suit and plaid tie. 29.6 x 19.5 cm., Undated; 4389; Studio Paul Tarkoul, Phebus, Constantinople (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Facial Hair; Turkey; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Men
- 43 girls from Zapyon Greek High School, seated and standing around two long tables. 24.9 x 32.8 cm, 1912; 4390; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Girls; Group Portraits; Furnishings; Greek Writing
- Bosphorus. View from the Asian shore towards the opposite European shoe with the Rumelihisari Castle across the water. 25.9 x 33.4 cm, Circa 1870; 4391; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Boats/Ships; Architecture; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Roumeli Hissar Castle; Albumen Prints; Bosphorus; Landscapes
- Group of people standing in front of a mosque in Adapazari. An imam stands in front of the group leading the prayer. 25 x 33 cm, Circa 1890; 4392; Studio Pantoykian (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Albumen Prints; Armenian Writing; Adapazari, Turkey; Greek Writing; Mosques; Group Portraits; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Buildings
- Yedikule Fortress in Constantinople with grass in the foreground and a house in front of the fort. 27 x 33.1 cm., Undated; 4393; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Forts/Castles; Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Architecture; Forts/Castles; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- Walls and battlements of the Yedikule Fortress, with patches of grass in front. 27.1 x 33.2 cm., Undated; 4394; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Forts/Castles
- Bird's eye view of Bursa. 26.6 x 35 cm., Circa 1870; 4395; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Houses; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Albumen Prints; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Bursa, Turkey
- Walls of Constantinople. 27.2 x 33 cm., Undated; 4396; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Architecture; Forts/Castles
- Three men in front of the Fountain of Sultan Ahmed III in the square outside the Topkapi Palace. 34 x 26 cm., 1860; 4397; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Smoking; Men; Topkapi Palace; Streets/Roads; Architecture; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Fountains; Arabic Calligraphy; Fountain of Sultan Ahmed III; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Palaces; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- Two men holding guns on the banks of the Jordan River. 21.7 x 27.8 cm, Circa 1910; 4401; American Colony, Jerusalem (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Palestine; Rivers; Outdoors; Weapons; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Jordan River; Regional/National Dress; Guns; Outdoors; Group Portraits; Men
- The Jordan River with a man standing in a rowboat on the bank. 28 x 35.7 cm, Circa 1910; 4403; American Colony, Jerusalem (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Outdoors; Boats/Ships; Rivers; Jordan River; Jordan
- Man in national dress standing on the banks of the Jordan river. 27.8 x 35.8 cm, Circa 1910; 4405; American Colony, Jerusalem (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Outdoors; Dead Sea; Rivers; Horses; Canes/Walking Sticks; Guns; Regional/National Dress; Jordan River; Jordan; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Animals; Weapons
- Man sitting by the Dead Sea beside a group of branches stacked in a pyramid for a fire. 28 x 36 cm, Circa 1910; 4406; American Colony, Jerusalem (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Dead Sea; Hats; Men; Palestine; Water
- View of Jericho from a distance with animals grazing in the foreground. 27.9 x 35.9 cm, Undated; 4408; American Colony, Jerusalem (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Landscapes; Animals; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Jericho; Outdoors; Palestine; Sheep; Bridges; English Writing; French Writing
- View of a river at the bottom of a rocky valley with a stone walkway built on the bank, a stone bridge in the middle-distance and a road built to the right. 27.8 x 35.1 cm, Undated; 4409; American Colony, Jerusalem (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Turkey; Bridges; Streets/Roads; Rivers; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Outdoors
- Egyptian woman wearing a hijab and niqab. 35.5 x 27.9 cm, Circa 1895; 4418; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Women; Individual Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Turkey; Niqab; Studio Photography; Regional/National Dress; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints
- Fountain of Sultan Ahmed III in the square outside the Topaki Palace. On reverse side of ref294. 30.3 x 40.5 cm, Undated; 4419; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Fountain of Sultan Ahmed III; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Fountains; Architecture; Topkapi Palace; Palaces
- Tomb of Sultan Mahmud II. On reverse side of ref293. 30.3 x 40.5 cm, Undated; 4420; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Tombs; Architecture; Buildings; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Tomb of Sultan Mahmud II and Abdulaziz; Istanbul, Turkey; Religious Sites
- Entrance to Yedikule Fortress with a few men sitting outside the gate smoking shisha. 29 x 38 cm, Circa 1860; 4421; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Smoking; Forts/Castles; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles
- Suleymaniye Mosque as seen from the Beyazit Tower. 28.5 x 36.8 cm, Circa 1880; 4422; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Architecture; Religious Sites; Bosphorus; Mosques; Istanbul, Turkey; Suleymaniye Mosque; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings
- Gate to Kucuksu Palace. On the reverse side of ref298. 27.4 x 36 cm, Circa 1870; 4423; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Guns; Architecture; Istanbul, Turkey; Kucuksu Palace; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Weapons; Palaces; Buildings
- Interior of the Hagia Sophia, Istanbul, Turkey. On the reverse side of ref297. 27.4 x 36 cm, Circa 1870; 4424; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Arabic Calligraphy; Hagia Sophia; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Religious Sites
- View of the Dome of the Rock and Al-Aqsa Mosque on the Temple Mount, Jerusalem. 30.3 x 40.5 cm, Undated; 4425; Bonfils, Felix (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Jerusalem; Religious Sites; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Architecture; Turkish Writing; Mosques; Al-Aqsa Mosque; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Palestine; Ottoman Writing
- Arial view of Bursa, Turkey with the Grand Mosque of Bursa (Ulucami) on the right. 30.6 x 40 cm, 1870; 4426; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Architecture; Bursa, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Grand Mosque of Bursa; Religious Sites
- Group photo of Ottoman soldiers in military uniforms holding gloves and swords. Addressing Sehzade Nurettin Efendi (1901-1944, son of Abdulhamit II) with the signature of Mulazim-i sani (second lieutenant) Nureddin (Nureddin Ibrahim Konyar, 1873 - 1932)." 27.8 x 38 cm, Undated; 4427; Studio August Töke, Photografie-Atelier, Bruck an der Leitha, filiale im K.U.K. Militar-Lager (Austria) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Swords/Knives; Group Portraits; Uniforms; Bruck, Austria; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Military/Soldiers; Gloves; Facial Hair; Weapons; Fezes/Tarbouches; Medals/Insignia
- "Crocodile a Port-Said" A German ship flying the German Empire flag docked in Port Said, Egypt. 27.8 x 35.1 cm, Ca. 1870; 4428; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Boats/Ships; Men; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Ports; Transportation; Lighthouses; Military/Soldiers; Port Said, Egypt
- Statue of Ibrahim Pasha in Cairo, Egypt. 35.8 x 28 cm, Undated; 4429; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Ibrahim Pasha; Men; Pasha; Cairo, Egypt; Statues/Sculptures; Photographic Prints
- Egyptian woman looking off to the right in a hijab and an ornamented veil. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; 4430; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Turkey; Head Covers/Veils; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewelry; Women
- Al Sayeda Zeinab Mosque in Cairo, Egypt. 27.7 x 21.3 cm, Undated; 4431; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Religious Sites; Al Sayeda Zeinab Mosque; Mosques; Women; Men; Animals; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Donkeys
- On the left, an ironclad ship with three masts; on the right, two more ships, all docked in Port Said, Egypt. 20.5 x 27 cm, Undated; 4432; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Men; Lighthouses; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Port Said, Egypt; Boats/Ships; Boats/Ships; Military/Soldiers
- Woman reclining on a chair, a shisha pipe hose in hand, slippered feet resting on two stacked cushions. On a table to the right there is a teacup and saucer and a shisha pipe. On reverse side of ref308. 23.6 x 29.9 cm, Undated; 4433; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Individual Portraits; Egypt; Tea/Coffee; Jewelry; Carpets/Rugs; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Women; Smoking; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles
- Woman looking off to the left, wearing a sheer, light-colored veil. Her hands, each with a ring, are crossed on a railing in front of her. On reverse side of ref307. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; 4434; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Individual Portraits; Egypt; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Head Covers/Veils; Painted Backdrops; Jewelry; Women
- Woman wearing a niqab, carrying a naked child on her shoulder. On reverse side of ref310. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; 4435; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Furnishings; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Children; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits; Niqab
- Arab woman holding a tarabuk, and a shisha (hookah) pipe on a small table with mother-of-pearl inlay sits to the left. On reverse side of ref309. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; 4436; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Singing; Women; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Musical Instruments; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Furnishings; Smoking; Egypt
- Woman in national dress on top of a saddled donkey. The donkey wears a adorned chain around its neck and a servant with a crop stands to the rear of the donkey. On reverse side of ref312. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; 4437; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Egypt; Jewelry; Animals; Donkeys; Regional/National Dress; Women; Group Portraits
- Two women, one standing, holding a two-handled pot on her head and one crouching, her left hand resting on a piece of pottery. On reverse side of ref311. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; 4438; Studio Photo Varjabedian, Zagazig, Egypt (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Pottery; Doors/Entrances; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Jewelry; Women; Group Portraits